Compared to most languages,
与大多数语言相比
Python has a large standard library.
Python 包含的标准库非常庞大
In fact, people say Python comes with batteries
实际上 有人说 Python 就像带有电池
included because it comes with the libraries you need to get right to work.
因为它包含你立即工作所需的库
However, the standard library doesn't come with everything you might want.
但是 标准库并非具有所有你可能想要的内容
Some tasks are too specialized to be accommodated by the standard library.
某些任务非常特殊 无法通过标准库实现
Fortunately, there are tens of thousands of
幸运的是 独立开发者编写了
third-party libraries written by independent developers.
成千上万的第三方库
How do we get these packages though,
如果这些软件包没有包含在 Python 本身中
if they aren't included with Python itself?
如何获取这些软件包？
We can install libraries using pip,
我们可以使用 pip 安装库
a package manager that is included with Python 3.
pip 是在 Python 3 中包含的软件包管理器
Pip is a standard package manager for Python, but it isn't the only one.
pip 是标准 Python 软件包管理器 但并不是唯一的管理器
One popular alternative is Anaconda,
另一个热门的管理器是 Anaconda
which is designed specifically for data science.
该管理器专门针对数据科学
Here, we'll use pip,
在这节课中我们将使用 pip
which is a general standard.
pip 是一般标准
Let's use pip to install this library,
我们使用 pip 安装这个库
which is used for working with time zones or remarkably complicated task.
该库用于处理时区或非常复杂的任务
This command will download and install the package,
这个命令将下载并安装该软件包
so that it's available to import in our programs.
使我们能够将其导入我们的程序中
Once installed, we can import third-party packages
安装完毕后 我们可以使用导入标准库的同一语法
using the same syntax we used to import from the standard library.
导入第三方软件包
In this example, I import
在此示例中
a time zone package along with a datetime from the standard library.
我从该标准库中导入了 timezone 软件包和 datetime 软件包
It's standard practice to put the import statements for
标准做法是将第三方库的导入语句
third-party libraries after imports from the standard library.
放在标准库的导入语句后面
This example stores the current time expressed in terms of
这个示例将用协调世界时 (UTC) 表示的当前时间
Coordinated Universal Time or UTC in the variable now.
存储在变量 now 中
It then translates this time into IST,
然后将此时间转换为印度标准时 (IST)
Indian Standard Time and stores that in the variable ist_now.
并存储到变量 ist_now 中
Larger Python programs might depend on dozens of third-party packages.
大型 Python 程序可能取决于大量第三方库
To make it easier to share these programs,
为了更轻松地共享这些程序
programmers often list of projects dependencies in a file called requirements.txt.
程序员经常将项目依赖项放在一个叫做 requirements.txt 的文件中
This is an example of a requirements.txt file.
这是一个 requirements.txt 文件示例
Each line of the file includes the name of a package and it's version number.
该文件的每行都包含软件包的名称和版本号
The version number is technically optional,
版本号是可选的
but it usually should be included.
但是通常应该包含版本号
Libraries can change subtly or dramatically between versions,
不同版本的库可能变化不大 也可能有巨大差异
so it's important to use
务必使用程序员的作者在编写程序时
the same library versions that the program's author used when they wrote the program.
使用的相同库版本
You can use pip to install all of the project's dependencies at once with this command.
你可以使用此命令通过 pip 安装项目的所有依赖项